Okay, so in order to understand why you
might want to pass a function into
another function, um we need to talk
about what happens to a variable when it
gets passed to a function. So I am going
to create a function here and I'm going
to call it clean up string and it's
going to take in um a messy string
and then I'm going to do some stuff with
that string. Well, the first thing I
want to do is I want to set messy string
equal to itself. Um, but where I've
trimmed off extra spaces. The next thing
I want to do is I probably want to set
messy string equal to itself, but where
I've
changed everything to uppercase
and then I want to return this back to
the main program. So, I wrote this out
in longhand, but I really want to show
you that you can simplify this a lot.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to
reduce this down to return messy
string.trim.
And then once I've trimmed it, I want to
do two uppercase.
Now that means that any string that I
give this should come back without any
spaces at the front, the back and it
should also be completely uppercase. So
let's create a variable my var and set
it oh sorry let my var and set it equal
to an empty string. And actually, let's
put a lot of spaces in the front, the
word hello, and then a lot of spaces at
the end.
And then I'm going to create let results
and I'm going to set it equal to cleanup
string. And I'm going to pass in my var.
And then we'll alert results. So let's
go over to our
running website and we'll reload the
page. And we get hello.
And then if we inspect the page, um I'll
prove to you that it really did remove
those spaces. Let's put a break point
here. Reload the page. And if we hit
next, um we pass it into the string.
Messy string is hello with a lot of
spaces. And then we're going to trim it
and turn it to uppercase. We hit next.
It returns it. If we hover over result,
we can see that it's just hello all in
uppercase. And therefore, our function
worked. Now, why is this important?
Well, this is important because it tells
us that when we pass a variable into our
function, it maintains all of its
attributes that it had before. So, just
like you can trim a string and convert
it to uppercase, if you pass in a
function, you can call it inside of
another function. And we will do that in
the next